<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jenny Listman</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jenny Listman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 12:21:16 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Women Running for Office</title>
      <link>/projects/interactivewebapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 12:21:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/interactivewebapp/</guid>
      <description>I created this interactive web app with data scraped from CAWP. They research women&amp;rsquo;s participation in politics maintain a list of women running for US Congress and State offices.
I wrote code to scrape and combine data from their lists, create new variables, and visualize the data in an interactive map and searchable data table.
See the app in action here and read a blog post about it here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rats &amp; New Yorkers: Neighbors</title>
      <link>/projects/nycrats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 12:21:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/nycrats/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>State Gun Laws &amp; Gun Deaths: Regression Tree</title>
      <link>/projects/gunlaws/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 12:21:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/gunlaws/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gun Deaths and Gun Laws: Recursive Partitioning and Regression Tree</title>
      <link>/blog/gun-deaths-and-gun-laws-recursive-partitioning-and-regression-tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/gun-deaths-and-gun-laws-recursive-partitioning-and-regression-tree/</guid>
      <description>This project uses a Recursive Partitioning And Regression Tree analysis from the rpart package to examine the effect of 49 gun law subcategories on annual State firearm death rates. Ten subcategories were found to significantly predict State gun death rate decreases or increases.  Data files needed to run this code can be found in my GitHub repo associated with the project.Read the blog post about it here and see the readme file for the infographic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scraping The CAWP Site To Make a Shiny App To Search For Women Running For Office</title>
      <link>/blog/scraping-the-cawp-site-to-make-a-shiny-app-to-search-for-women-running-for-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/scraping-the-cawp-site-to-make-a-shiny-app-to-search-for-women-running-for-office/</guid>
      <description>Interactive App To Visualize Women Runnning for State or Federal Offices This project was created with data scraped from the website of the Center for American Women in Politics at Rutgers University. The Center conducts research on women’s participation in politics in America and maintains a list of women who are or potentially will be running for US Congress and State offices.
The code scrapes and combines data from their lists of women candidates, cleans and creates new variables, and visualizes the data in an interactive shiny map and searchable data table using plotly and DT packages .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 13:23:28 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 13:19:25 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I can help your nonprofit or small business:  Get your data into a useable format and find data that you might not know you have. Analyze, summarize, &amp;amp; visualize your data to provide insight to you or your potential investors, clients, or donors. Tell your story with data. Analyse data through clustering, decision trees, and other machine learning tools.  I have interdisciplinary training:  B.A. in Biology, University of Pennsylvania in 1991 PhD in Anthropological Genetics, New York University in 2009 Postdoc at Yale University School of Medicine, Psychiatric Genetics in 2011  I&amp;rsquo;m experienced in data wrangling, big data, machine learning, clustering, and data visualization.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>