<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R Code on Jenny Listman</title>
    <link>/categories/r-code/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R Code on Jenny Listman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/r-code/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Gun Deaths &amp; Gun Laws: Recursive Partitioning And Regression Tree</title>
      <link>/post/gun-deaths-gun-laws-recursive-partitioning-and-regression-tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/gun-deaths-gun-laws-recursive-partitioning-and-regression-tree/</guid>
      <description>This project uses a Recursive Partitioning And Regression Tree analysis from the rpart package to examine the effect of 49 gun law subcategories on annual State firearm death rates. Ten subcategories were found to significantly predict State gun death rate decreases or increases.  Read the blog post about it here and see the readme file for the infographic. Load packages
library(tidyverse) library(rpart) library(janitor) library(stringr) library(readxl) library(Metrics) library(rlist) Obtain and read in datasets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scraping The CAWP Site To Make a Shiny App To Search For Women Running For Office</title>
      <link>/blog/scraping-the-cawp-site-to-make-a-shiny-app-to-search-for-women-running-for-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/scraping-the-cawp-site-to-make-a-shiny-app-to-search-for-women-running-for-office/</guid>
      <description>Interactive App To Visualize Women Runnning for State or Federal Offices This project was created with data scraped from the website of the Center for American Women in Politics at Rutgers University. The Center conducts research on women’s participation in politics in America and maintains a list of women who are or potentially will be running for US Congress and State offices.
The code scrapes and combines data from their lists of women candidates, cleans and creates new variables, and visualizes the data in an interactive shiny map and searchable data table using plotly and DT packages .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>